EPISODE 4: ALLEN SPILLS THE BEANS
How can I get out of this? Gotta think fast!
Help me out, Sucker!
Awesome! That did some damage!
I never tested it to be sure, but I was right
about these guys having an energy drain attack!
I'm weaker after losing so many
of my summons and their buffs,
but that's not a problem
if I can just cripple this thing instead!
Fido! Sucker!
YOU HAVE DEFEATED 1 ALBAHERON.
YOU HAVE GAINED 100 EXP.
Oh, man...
I WOOOOON!
I beat my first monster!
This is giving me a rush beyond words!
An albaheron?!
Look what I got!
How did you manage that?!
It happened to land nearby,
so I took it by surprise!
That's mostly true.
You're amazing, Allen!
It's scawy!
Don't worry, Mash. It won't move or anything.
Hey. You've got a cut on your cheek.
Are you hurt anywhere else?
The bleeding stopped already. I'm fine!
This is real impressive, kid. You took it down
with your wooden sword and some rocks?
Yep!
Uh, I see some dog-like bite marks here.
Huh?!
Did you bite it, Allen?
Oh crap!
I-I'm not sure, I was fighting on pure instinct...
Chomp! Chomp! Chomp! Chomp! Chomp! Chomp!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Oh, right.
Rodin. I'll bleed it out for ya.
Thanks. Please do.
Wow! That's one big lump.
Bet he got that while playing knights with Krena.
Gerda must be slow on his feet.
Hey, Allen.
Lend me a hand.
Albaherons weigh 60 kilos on average.
That drops to 20 kilos after you
drain the blood and dry 'em out.
Only half of that is edible meat, though.
Their wings fetch a pretty penny, too.
I'm happy he's willing to teach me all this!
Though, we still gotta fork over
most of it to the upper class.
Huh? The sixty percent tax
even applies to wild monsters?
Yep.
They're nice enough to overlook
smaller ones like E-rank horned rabbits.
But albaherons are D-rank.
What a bum deal.
One more thing.
Almost... got it!
This is a magic stone.
Oh yeah?
Magic stones from any monster
above D-rank fall under the tax.
No biggie, though.
They're worthless to us in the village anyways.
But listen!
A kid like you wouldn't be out there catching
monsters if your dad hadn't gotten hurt so bad.
We can use that as leverage
to negotiate a bigger cut with the chieftain.
Oh, I see.
I think I have an idea, Mister Gerda!
Whisper, whisper, whisper.
CHIEFTAIN'S RESIDENCE
So, there you have it.
Rodin's youngster stuck his little neck out
to nab this monster.
Ah, I see! Wonderful!
Here's the deal.
Huh?
We'll fork over the entirety of its wings as tax.
But you don't mind us taking the rest, yeah?
Ah, I see. Wonder-fuh?
C'mon. That's not such a big deal, is it?
Wait, wait, wait!
That's a problem!
The baron has asked that we deliver
even more meat this year, you see.
You understand what that means, right?
Huh? The baron did?
Is that why the chief was so insistent
on having commoners join the hunt?
You drive a hard bargain.
Fine, we'll throw in
the magic stone, too. How's that?
Huh? Just the wings and the magic stone?
Well, shucks! If only SOMEBODY
hadn't asked the impossible of us.
Then maybe our resident hero, Rodin,
wouldn't have gotten hurt so badly.
Now his poor family is on the verge
of starving to death.
How can they survive the winter
with four mouths to feed?
Oh! I'm so hungry!
It's making me dizzy...
Oh no, Allen! Hang in there!
Heavens me! Just WHO can we blame
for this awful predicament?
Aw, all right! I get it!
I do owe a lot to Rodin for his work.
I suppose you can have it.
Boom, baby! That's how we do it!
Thank you, chief!
Don't mention it...
So, in the future, we can keep the meat and just
give you the wings and magic stones, right?
Huh?!
This is the real crux of the issue!
Come now, Allen!
It's not good to count your albaherons
before they've hatched!
They're tough to get. Right, chief?
Way to sell him on it!
That's a good point.
I suppose you can keep the meat if you're
lucky enough to wrangle another one. Do your best.
It's a done deal!
Ribbit. Ribbit. Ribbit. Ribbit. Ribbit. Ribbit.
Whoa! Two of them?!
Hopper! That's enough!
Ribbit. Ribbit. Ribbit.
Suck 'em dry!
Take this!
Give 'em the fangs, Fido!
Knock 'em down!
And make it double!
Woot! Now that's what I call a two for one!
Okay, everybody! Return!
I've been out hunting once every three days
since beating that first one,
but this is the first time
I didn't lose any summons!
Flawless victory, baby!
YOU HAVE DEFEATED
2 ALBAHERONS.
YOU HAVE GAINED 200 EXP.
Sweet.
YOUR EXP HAS REACHED
THE MAX OF 1000/1000.
Huh?
YOU HAVE GONE UP
TO LEVEL 2.
Show me that stat page!
NAME:
INTELLIGENCE:
LUCK:
AGE:
TALENT:
LEVEL:
HP:
MP:
ATTACK:
ENDURANCE:
AGILITY:
ALLEN
SUMMONER
I recovered all my HP and MP after leveling up!
SKILLS:
SUMMON (3), CREATE (3), FUSE (3)
EHHANCE (2), EXPANSION (2), DELETE
SWORD MASTERY (3), THROW (3)
EXP:
0/2000
But my stat increases are only 60%
SKILL LEVELS
SUMMON: 3
CREATE: 3
FUSE: 3
EHHANCE:2
EXP
of the total they should be.
Guess I don't get the full benefits
SUMMONS AVAILABLE FOR CREATION:
INSECTS: FGH, BEASTS: FGH, BIRDS: FG, PLANTS: F
INVENTORY:
INSECTS F 2 COPIES, G 3 COPIES
BEASTS F 16 COPIES
BIRDS F 2 COPIES
PLANT F 7 COPIES
of the level up yet.
That's rough.
Well, whatever.
Yes! Hell yes! I did it!
HP HAS GONE UP BY 25
MP HAS GONE UP BY 40
ATTACK HAS GONE UP BY 14
ENDURANCE HAS GONE UP BY 14
AGILITY HAS GONE UP BY 26
INTELLIGENCE HAS GONE UP BY 40
LUCK HAS GONE UP BY 26
I leveled up!
Alright! Those are big gains!
Bring it in.
Six years after being reincarnated.
I've finally hit my first level up.
So this is what it's like to pass
a "Trial of the Gods", huh?
Feels amazing.
It might be time that I
let the fam in on the truth.
I'm home!
Oh, welcome back.
Whoa! You caught two of them today?!
Yep! I actually beat them at the same time.
Pretty amazing, huh?
Huh? Wait a sec, Allen...
What is it?
Never mind. It's nothing.
Ah! I gotta go!
With today's hunt,
I've met my goal of 10 monsters.
Once I dry the meat,
we'll have enough to make it through winter!
The only thing left now is to trade for firewood!
Since there are a lot of albaherons around
for migration season,
I could try to hit level three by hunting 20 more.
But that'll be hard to do
before the end of the year.
Huh?
Ow!
See ya tomorrow!
So, you wanted to talk with us?
Yeah. This might throw you for a loop, but...
to tell the truth, I heard an oracle from God
back when I was one year old.
An oracle?
Are you talking about Lord Elmea?
That's right.
"Young Allen. I shall bless you
with power and wisdom."
So he said!
What is that supposed to mean, exactly?
It basically means I'm smarter
and physically stronger than your average person.
But at the same time...
"You shall be faced with trials beyond
what even a hundred men could accomplish."
"Use your blessings of power
and wisdom to overcome them."
So, yeah!
A hundred men?!
Oh, Lord! How could you do this to my Allen?!
I see. You must have bested
one of those trials today, huh?
You probably haven't noticed, but the cut you had
on your cheek this morning has disappeared.
Huh? Oh...
I know what it's like to pass a Trial of the Gods.
I figured that's what happened with you.
Oh yeah?
Wait, but what about your results
from last year's Appraisal Ceremony?
I got another oracle from Elmea
about that a couple months ago.
Jeez, that recently?!
But wait a minute, show proper respect!
That's LORD Elmea to you, got it?
Sure, I'll be careful from now on.
Good.
The reason my attributes were ranked so low
at the Appraisal Ceremony
is because they take the slower progression
of my trials into account.
And the reason I was judged not to have a talent
is because mine was actually
too new to be recognized.
Wait, so you DO have a talent?
What kind is it?
Well, he never told me what it was...
Shoot.
Sorry, Dad. I can't say anything
about being a Summoner yet.
I'm worried some people
might get the wrong idea
if they find out I can summon
and control creatures.
And naturally, I can't tell anybody
that I was reincarnated.
Oh, Allen! I wish you would have told us sooner!
Your habit of throwing
those rocks at trees every day,
and now hunting these big monsters,
it's because you've been fighting
to overcome the Lord's trial, huh?
And all by yourself!
I'm sorry, Mom.
You little dummy.
So, what are you going to do now?
Well...
I want to prove myself worthy
by passing the trials.
So I'll be brave and take them head-on.
All right. I figured as much.
Lord Elmea prepared this challenge
specifically for you.
It's worth taking up the gauntlet.
And if you run into trouble,
don't hesitate to ask for our help.
Okay.
Thanks so much! Dad, Mom!
Hey, Allen? Keep this all between us for now.
It would be bad if anyone took you
for a false prophet.
But... do you mind if I tell Gerda?
Huh? Sure, that's fine with me.
Okay, great!
He's always bragging about
how Krena's a Sword Lord and all.
Now I can tell him that my son
is just as incredible!
THE HARDCORE GAMER DOMINATES
IN ANOTHER WORLD WITH GARBAGE BALANCING
ALLEN - AGE 6
Well, I always figured you were no ordinary kid.
But getting blessed and tested
by God is something else.
It explains a lot, though.
Rodin must be beside himself.
This is your first time
trading for supplies, yeah?
Yes. Please show me the ropes.
Good thing you stocked up on those albaheron, eh?
Seems like your boar hunt was fruitful, too!
Things go smoothly when it's just us serfs
and no commoners to muck it up!
What's the real difference
between serfs and commoners, anyway?
Well, our social standing, for one.
Also our taxes. The sixty percent rule
doesn't apply to commoners.
They have what's called a "head tax" instead.
They pay three gold coins for each adult
and one for each kid every year.
Oh, that's interesting.
And now, I slip in my real question...
Is there any way for serfs to become commoners?
There is. You gotta make a tribute
of 10 gold coins per person in the family.
I've also heard stories that the baron
can reward people with commoner status,
but I dunno if that's true or not.
I see.
My family's about to get a new member.
So it would cost us 50 gold coins, huh?
I'm trading in five packs of boar jerky.
Okay, I'll do the same.
I'd like to trade in five packs
of albaheron jerky.
Awesome!
Here ya go.
Whoa!
One pack of jerky trades
for four days worth of firewood.
Now that I know how bartering works,
I can do a bit of market research
next time I'm here.
Thank you, sir.
May I ask how much
this would cost to buy with money?
Five silver coins.
Thanks.
Can't be a salt merchant without
a "salty" attitude, I guess.
What is that fruit hanging down over there?
We call those "popos".
They trade one-for-one with a bundle of your meat.
Jeez, expensive! That's four times
the rate for molmos.
You want one of those instead?
No, sir! I'll keep these.
A single bundle of albaheron jerky trades for:
One bag of salt.
Four molmo fruits.
One popo fruit.
Four days worth of firewood.
The following forms of currency
have the same value:
One gold coin. A hundred silver coins.
A thousand copper coins. Ten thousand iron coins.
One bundle of jerky goes for one silver coin.
So saving up for 50 gold coins would mean...
hunting 500 albaherons.
Nice. That would only take a few years!
A walk in the park for a hardcore gamer like me!
Pardon me!
Do you have any medicines that recover MP?
Huh?
We don't carry anything that fancy 'round here.
Oh, really?
Where are the healing medicines?
Towards the back.
I wonder if my notebook can make drawings, too?
Oh! It worked!
It pays to try things out. Which reminds me...
Excuse me, which of these is the muellerze flower?
I don't have any of those!
And even if I did, I won't cut any deals for it!
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeesh. I'm still frustrated
over the last one I sold.
Do you mean the one Mister Gerda
bought about a month ago?
Yeah, exactly! That darn Gerda fellow!
He burst in here all of a sudden and demanded
my best medicine. He was beyond insistent!
And so, you sold him a muellerze flower?
Well, I happened to have one in stock that day.
But when I told him it cost five gold coins,
he begged me to settle
for three and promised to pay later.
He kept hollering about some friend needing help.
He even dropped to his hands and knees!
Gerda's a real bro...
Anyways, the guy was more persistent than a kid
at a candy store. I had to let him have it.
But I was biting my nails like crazy
until he brought the money.
Still, it was a bad deal. I lost out in the end.
It really irks me!
Here. For you.
Oh, sorry for going off like that!
You're here to trade, right?
What would you like? Just let me know.
No. I'm giving this to you.
Huh? What for?
You did a great service selling that muellerze
flower at a discount. It saved my father's life.
Oh my...
This is a token of my appreciation.
I'll bring more next time!
Thank you, sir.
Aw, don't mention it.
Holy crap! Just one of those
costs 50 silver coins?!
That's five albaherons...
Hey!
Whatchu want with my family's shop, dirthead?
This joker again.
Guess his dad is a blacksmith, huh?
That's the chieftain's son hanging out with him.
Nothing in particular. Bye.
Take this!
What was that for?!
You only get to pass if you agree to be my minion!
Who does he think he is,
a player killer in an MMO?
PVP doesn't score any EXP,
so I usually never bother with it.
What's wrong? You chicken out already?
Th-that's not fair!
You think that excuse will work
on the battlefield?
Mister tough guy.
Go grab whatever weapon you want.
I'll wait right here.
Fine! You better not run, punk!
Keep an eye on him, Pelmoas!
Hi there, Pelmoas.
Uh, hey, Allen.
I'll give you some credit!
You had the balls to stick around!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Cheap move!
His attacks hit pretty hard.
Makes sense for an Axe User.
But he hardly compares
to the three-star power of Krena.
What's the big idea? Come at me, already!
Dogora, Knight of the Axe.
I'll be back to trade at your store someday.
See ya.
Dammit!
Feast your eyes. I'm back in tip-top shape!
Just don't pull a muscle by overexerting yourself.
Right!
AT KRENA'S HOUSE
Ow!
When will you learn, Dogora?
I told you to anticipate my moves.
Yeah, I know!
Why can't I land a hit, dammit?!
Hiyah!
I can tell Krena's taking it super easy on him.
But Mash is doing pretty good, actually.
He might have the talent of a Spear User!
You're wide open!
Ouch!
Big brudder! I like this thing!
Oh yeah? That's great!
I'm excited to see how
your Appraisal Ceremony will go in two years!
Dammit! I'm not done yet!
Wow, Myulla is so cute!
There was a time you were this cute, too.
My own little prince charming.
Shucks...
I'm back.
Welcome home!
You're later than usual.
And Mister Gerda's with you?
We were summoned by the chieftain.
Here's the deal.
The cheftain wants us to raise the number of boars
that we deliver to the baron from 10 to 15.
And to make that happen, he expects us to let
the commoners join the hunt again this year.
Ridiculous! After you suffered that awful injury?!
We wanted to say no, of course.
But this order came directly
from the baron, apparently.
If we don't deliver 15 boars by winter this year,
they're going to recruit
more serfs from elsewhere.
More serfs in the village
results in less land to go around.
Which means that serfs who can't hunt
might have their land taken away from them.
And that risks changing
the very nature of Krena Village.
Worse yet, they want us
to hunt 20 boars next year.
No way! That's impossible!
The only way to make it happen is for us to hunt
more often than the usual once every ten days.
But that just means greater risks
for everyone involved!
The opinions of a few serfs can't compete
with the orders of the baron.
No matter how unfair it seems.
This is awful!
Yeah, it's not fair. But...
We don't have the luxury of choice.
Okay, let's say that you
increase the number of hunts.
Then they'll just keep expecting more from you
over the years, until it soon becomes impossible.
The ultimate result is still
recruiting more serfs, right?
Hey, Allen. Don't interupt when the adults are-
Yeah. You make a good point.
Are you suggesting we do what the chieftain says
and let commoners join the hunt again?
Pretty much.
Out of the question!
Those fools are nothing but dead weight!
Then you have to find a way to make them useful.
Listen. I have wisdom
that was blessed to me by Lord Elmea.
I've spent countless hours across numerous games,
making characters as strong
as they could possibly be.
Both flying solo and in pairs.
I know how to integrate a newbie into a party
so they can safely gain the necessary EXP.
Will you let me handle all this?
I think I know how to make it work.